William Mansfield Clark Papers 1903-1964 Mss.B.C547
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1903-1964; 3.5 lin. feet
  - Roseman, Saul (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Harris, Joseph
  - Rosenau, M. J. (Box 6)
  - Rosenberg, Lawson, L., 1953-1960 (Box 6)
    Carnes, William H.
    Lever, Walter F.
    Simpson, Miriam E.
  - Rosenberg, Mollie Cohen (Mrs. William), 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - Rossini, Frederick D., 1958 (Box 6)
  - Royal Society of Arts, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Ruskin, Simon L., 1952 (Box 6)
  - Salomon, Alfred V., 1952 (Box 6)
  - Sanadi, D. Rao, 1960 (Box 6)
    -see also Ser. IV, [Oxidation-Reduction Potentials of Organic Systems]
  - Sanders, Howard J. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Chemical and Engineering News
  - Santiago, Silvia, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Sarles, William Bowen (Box 6)
  - W. B. Saunders Company, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Savage, W. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Lowe, Harry J.
  - Scatchard, George, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Scherp, Henry W. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Berry, George Packer
  - Schmidt, Carl F. (Box 6)
  - Schmidt, Carl L. A., 1921 (Box 6)
  - Schmitt, Francis O., 1950 (Box 6)
  - Schoenbach, Emanuel B., 1950 (Box 6)
  - Schramm, J. R. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Biological Abstracts
  - Science, 1959, 1963 (Box 6)
    Abelson, Philip H.
    Zwarenstein, H.
  - Semmes, Bowen & Semmes, 1934 (Box 6)
  - Sendroy, Julius, Jr., 1952, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Shack, Joseph (Box 6)
  - Shaffer, G. Wilson (Box 6)
  - Shaffer, Philip A., 1927-1928, 1951 (Box 6)
  - Shannon, James A. (Box 6)
  - Shaw, Roscoe H., 1923 (Box 6)
  - Shelton, Robert S. (Box 6)
  - Sherfy, Carrie B. (Box 6)
  - Sherman, H. C., 1919, 1925 (Box 6)
  - Sherman, James M., 1924, 1934, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Shocket, Everett, 1951-1952 (Box 6)
  - Shorr, Ephriam (Box 6)
  - Shreve, (Col.) Arthur L. (Box 6)
  - Shriner, Ralph L., 1944, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Shryock, Richard H., 1950 (Box 6)
    -see also Ser. I, Buehler, Reginald
  - Sigerist, Henry E., 1934 (Box 6)
    -see also Ser. II, Sigerist, Henry E.
  - Simenhoff, Michael, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Simmons, (Gen.) James S., 1943-1944 (Box 6)
    Gentzkow, C. J.
    Robinson, (Lt. Col.) Elliott S.
    -see also Ser. I, Lea & Febiger
    -see also Ser. IV, "Acid-Base Indicators"
  - Simpson, Miriam E. (Box 6)
  - Smith, Constance (Box 6)
  - Smith, Cyril Stanley, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Smith, Gilbert B. L. (Box 6)
  - Smith, Homer W., 1954 (Box 6)
    -see also Ser. I, Office of Scientific Research and Development
  - Smith, Lee Irvin, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Snell, Esmond E. (Box 6)
  - Sobotka, Harry, 1948 (Box 6)
  - The Society of American Bacteriologists, 1925, 1932-1934, 1952-1959 (Box 6)
    Dubos, René J.
    Foster, E. M.
    Fred, E. B.
    Hucker, G. J.
    Rosenau, M. J.
    Sherman, James M.
    Tanner, F. W.
    -see also Ser. I, Journal of Bacteriology
    -see also Ser. II, The Society of American Bacteriologists...
    -see also Ser. IV, "An Outline of the History of Studies on Anaerobiosis"
  - Sørensen, S. P. L., 1924, 1928 (Box 6)
  - Spade, H. Novoa, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Spahr, John F. (Box 6)
  - Spaulding, John H. (Box 6)
  - Sperry, Warren M. (Box 6)
  - [Stadie?], Catherine (Mrs. William C.), 1960 (Box 6)
  - Stadie, William C., 1934, 1943 (Box 6)
  - Stanley, Wendell M. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, University of California (Berkeley). Virus Laboratory
  - Stare, F. J. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Fred, E. B.
  - Starr, Charles D. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Phi Lambda Upsilon
  - [Steglitz], Julius, 1922 (Box 6)
    Cox, Henry L.
    Jacobsohn, I. M.
  - Stein, Milton F., 1921 (Box 6)
  - Stein, William H., 1952 (Box 6)
  - Theodor Steinkopff Verlagsbuchhandlung, 1931-1932 (Box 6)
  - Steinwald, Osmar P. (Box 6)
  - Stetten, DeWitt, Jr. (Box 6)
  - Stevens, Raymond, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Stimson, Henry L. (Box 6)
  - Stock, C. Chester (Box 6)
  - Stockard, C. R. (Box 6)
  - Stotz, Elmer H. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Symposium on Teaching Practices in Biochemistry
  - Streeter, George (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Mayer, Joseph E.
  - Sumner, Francis B., 1937 (Box 6)
    WMC's brother-in-law
  - [Sumner], Herbert, 1939 (Box 6)
  - [Sumner?], John, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Sumner, Margaret (Clark), 1955, n.d. (Box 6)
    "Daisy," WMC's sister
    Cuthbert, (Rev.) John S.
  - The Sun (Baltimore, Md.), 1950 (Box 7)
  - Swain, R. C. (Box 7)
  - Sweet, L. A. (Box 7)
  - Symposium on Teaching Practices in Biochemistry, 1955 (Box 7)
    Stotz, Elmer
  - Szent-Györgyi, Albert V., [1926] (Box 7)
  - Tahmisian, T. N. (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, Argonne National Laboratory
  - Tainter, [M.] L. (Box 7)
  - Tappan, Benjamin, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Tanner, F. W. (Box 7)
  - Tarbett, R. E. (Box 7)
    -see Ser. V, Tarbett, R. E.
    "Outline and Recommendations Covering Experimental Work..."
  - Tatum, Edward L. (Box 7)
  - Taylor, John FullerMansfield Clark - An Appreciation", 1951-1959 (Box 7)
    -see also Ser. V, Taylor, John Fuller. "Wm.
  - Taylor, W. Rowland (Box 7)
    Herriott, Roger M.
  - Taylor, Wesley A. (Box 7)
  - Taylor Instrument Companies, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Te Linde, Richard W. (Box 7)
  - Temkin, Owsei, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Theorell, Hugo, 1952-1954, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Theriault, Emery J. (Box 7)
  - Thimann, Kenneth V., 1953 (Box 7)
  - Thomas, Charles C. (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, Charles C. Thomas, Publisher
  - Thomas, Martha Reynolds (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, Columbia University
  - Arthur H. Thomas Company, 1926, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Charles C. Thomas, Publisher, 1928, 1943 (Box 7)
    -see also Ser. I, The Williams & Wilkins Company
  - Thompson, James S. (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc.
  - Thornton, H. R., 1927 (Box 7)
  - [Tillmans], 1925-1926 (Box 7)
  - Time, 1958 (Box 7)
    re: treatment of Linus Pauling
  - Tinker, J. M. (Box 7)
  - Trout, William E., Jr., 1946 (Box 7)
  - Tucker, Edgar S. (Box 7)
  - Tuke, Charles H., 1953 (Box 7)
  - Turner, Tommy (Box 7)
  - Unidentified, 1923-1963, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Union Internationale De Biochimie (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, International Union of Biochemistry. Committee on Enzymes
  - Union Nationale Des Intellectuels (Box 7)
  - [US] Army Medical School, 1920 (Box 7)
  - US Army, Office of Chief of Chemical Warfare Service (Box 7)
  - US Civil Service Commission (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, Blanchard, Kenneth Clark
  - US Department of Agriculture, 1910-1944, n.d. (Box 7)
    Alsberg, Carl L.
    Ambler, Joseph A.
    Fellers, C. R.
    Harding, T. Swann
    Holm, George E.
    Leviton, A.
    Phillips, E. F.
    Rawl, B. H.
    Roberts, R. W.
    Sherfy, Carrie B.
    Wherry, Edgar T.
    Zoller, Harper F.
    -see also Ser. I, Rogers, Lore A.
    -see also Ser. VI, Potassium Indigotine
  - US Department of Commerce, 1922, n.d. (Box 7)
    Blum, [W?]
    Hynson, Westcott & Dunning
    Jackson, R. [T.]
  - US Public Health Service. Bureau of Standards, 1920-1926, 1947 (Box 7)
    Cooper, W. Clark
    Frost, W. H.
    Harper, J. E.
    McCoy, George W.
    Tarbett, R. E.
    Theriault, Emery J.
    Tucker, Edgar S.
    Shack, Joseph
    Warren, B. S.
    -see also Ser. II, US Public Health Service
  - US Public Health Service, National Institutes of Health, 1952-1953 (Box 7)
    Shorr, Ephriam
    Schmidt, Carl F.
    Watt, James
    Wiggers, Carl J.
    Yeager, J. Franklin
  - US War Department, 1947 (Box 7)
    re: "Methods for Laboratory Technicians" manual
    Doan, (Col.) H. W.
  - US War Manpower Commission, 1944 (Box 7)
  - University of California (Berkeley). Virus Laboratory, 1952 (Box 7)
    re: position for Harbury
    Stanley, Wendell M.
  - University of Chicago, 1927 (Box 7)
    Miller, C. Phillip, Jr.
    -see also Ser. II, University of Chicago
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1921 (Box 7)
    Pepper, William
  - University of Virginia. Medical School, 1958-1959 (Box 7)
    Dent, J. N.
    Pullen, E. W.
    -see also, Ser. I, Gemmill, Chalmers L.
  - U.S. Industrial Alcohol Co., 1920 (Box 7)
    Whitaker, M. C.
  - Van Campen, M. G., Jr. (Box 7)
  - Van Niel, C. B. (Box 7)
  - Van Rensselaer, 1948 (Box 7)
  - Van Santvoord, George (Box 7)
  - Van Slyke, Donald D., 1923-1955, n.d. (Box 7)
    -see also Ser. I, Lilly Research Grants Committee
  - Van Wyk, Judson J., 1952, 1955 (Box 7)
    The National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis
  - Vaughn, Reese H. (Box 7)
  - Vaughan, V. C. (Box 7)
  - Vestling, Carl S., 1948-1955 (Box 7)
    -see also Ser. I, Lowe, Harry J.
  - Vickery, H. B., 1949, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Volke, J., 1961 (Box 7)
  - Volwiler, E. H. (Box 7)
  - Waddington, Guy (Box 7)
  - Wadsö, Ingemar (Box 7)
  - Wagley, Philip F., 1954, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Thomas R. Wagner Agency, 1953, 1961 (Box 7)
    Lampson, Lucy
    Whitbeck, Charles
  - Wald, George, 1952, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Wallace, Robert L. (Box 7)
  - Wallace & Tiernan Co, Inc., 1920 (Box 7)
  - Walser, Mackenzie, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Walter, Robert I., n.d. (Box 7)
  - Warburg, Otto, 1937, 1948 (Box 7)
    Some in German; incl. re: NAS membership
    Doisy, E. A.
  - Warren, B. S. (Box 7)
  - Washburn, E. W. (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, International Critical Tables of Numerical Data of Physics, Chemistry and Technology
  - Washington (D.C.) Academy of Sciences, 1913, 1920, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Watt, James (Box 7)
  - Weaver, Warren, 1949, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Webb, [Edwin] C. (Box 7)
  - Weed, Lewis H. (Box 7)
    -see Ser. II, Weed, Lewis H.
    -see Ser. IV, "On the Retirement of Doctor Lewis Hill Weed..."
  - Weinbach, Eugene C. (Box 7)
  - Weisiger, James R., 1955 (Box 7)
  - Weissman, Norman (Box 7)
  - Welsbach Company, 1929 (Box 7)
    Miner, Harlan S.
  - Werkman, C. H., 1946 (Box 7)
  - Weston, G. (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, British Standards Institution
  - Wherry, Edgar T. (Box 7)
  - Whipple, George H., 1923, 1935, 1939 (Box 7)
    -see also Ser. II, "Biographical Memoir of Walter (Jennings) Jones, 1865-1935"
  - Whitaker, M. C., 1920 (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, U.S. Industrial Alcohol Co.
  - Whitbeck, Charles, 1961 (Box 7)
  - White, Roy Barton (Box 7)
    -see Ser. II, Willard, Daniel
  - Whitehorn, John C., 1949, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Whittemore, H. Lawrence, 1947, n.y. May 17 (Box 7)
  - Wieland, Heinrich, 1926 (Box 7)
  - Wiggers, Carl J. (Box 7)
  - John Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1941, 1952, 1961 (Box 7)
    Ehrensvärd, Gösta
    Wadsö, Ingemar
  - The Will Corporation, 1921 (Box 7)
  - Willard, Daniel, 1938-1942 (Box 7)
    -see also Ser. II, Willard, Daniel
  - Willard, Daniel, III (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, The Comet
  - Willard, Fred W. (Box 7)
  - Williams, E. F. (Box 7)
  - Williams, J. W. (Box 7)
  - Williams, J. Whitridge, 1927 (Box 7)
  - Williams College, 1907, 1934, 1937, 1959 (Box 7)
    Baxter, James P., 3rd
    Ferry, Frederick C.
    Mc Elfresh, William E.
    Mears, Brainerd
    Mears, Leverett
    Maxcy, Carroll L.
    -see also Ser. II, Williams College
  - The Williams & Wilkins Company (Box 7)
    Incl. royalty stmts, reviews, etc.
    Baetjer, Howard, II
    Hoover, Dick M.
    Moura Gonçalves, J.
    Thomas, Charles C.
    Williams, E. F.
    Williams, J. W.
    - Folder 1, 1927, 1944-1963 (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1946-1962 (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, 1960-1962 (Box 7)
    - Folder 4, 1946-1962 (Box 7)
  - Williamstown Massachusetts Public Schools, 1907 (Box 7)
    Recommends WMC
    DeCamp, John A.
  - Wilmer, William H., 1927 (Box 7)
  - Wilson, D. Wright (Box 7)
  - Wilson, Perry W., 1958 (Box 7)
    -see also Ser. I, Bacteriological Reviews
  - Winberg, Jack S., 1960 (Box 7)
  - Winslow, C. -E. A., 1917, 1934, 1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - Winternitz, M. C. (Box 7)
  - Wintersteiner, O[skar] (Box 7)
  - Winthrop Chemical Company (Box 7)
  - Winzler, Richard (Box 7)
  - Wisecup, William G., 1953 (Box 7)
  - Wiselogle, Frederick (Box 7)
  - Witherell, William R., 1952, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Wolfrom, M. L., 1940 (Box 7)
  - Wolman, Abel (Box 7)
  - Wood, James L., 1963 (Box 7)
    -see Ser. I, ACS Chemical Abstracts Service
  - Woods, Alan C., 1948-1952, 1961 (Box 7)
    -see also Ser. I, Hampden-Sydney College
  - Woodward, H. E., 1920 (Box 7)
  - World Biography, 1948, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Wrede, Fritz (Box 7)
  - [Wright] (Box 7)
  - Wurmser, Rene, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Wyllie, J., 1956 (Box 7)
  - Yeager, J. Franklin (Box 7)
  - Zeile, Karl, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Zoller, Harper F. (Box 7)
  - Zwarenstein, H. (Box 7)
- Series II. Subject files, 1903-1964; 2 boxes, 1 lin. foot
  Bibliographies and curricula vitae for a number of individuals; photocopies of clippings, especially regarding awards and honors; letters, grouped by publication title, from friends and colleagues regarding works recently published by Clark; announcements and programs for lectures, learned society meetings, testimonial dinners and luncheons; materials documenting commencement exercises at the Johns Hopkins University and Medical School; invitations; playbills and entertainment event programs; class exams and attendance lists; committee rosters, especially from Clark's work at the National Academy of Sciences / National Research Council during World War II; meeting memoranda and minutes; letters patent; a certificate of copyright; some reprints; letters to Clark, and other material, regarding a bacteria-based electricity source, or "Bug Battery"; golf score cards; and a receipt for tuition paid. Also included in this series are copies of Clark's bibliography covering publications until the 1950's. Biographical material regarding Clark, and information about Clark family history and genealogy is also filed here.
  - AAAS, 1914 (Box 8)
  - ACS, 1928, 1942-1948 (Box 8)
  - ACS Maryland Section, Maryland Chemist Award, 1963 (Box 8)
    -see also Ser. IV, "[Illustrations of a Chemical Continuum"]
  - ACS New York Section, William H. Nichols Medal, 1936; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - American Pharmaceutical Manufacturers' Association, 1944 (Box 8)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1945-1955 (Box 8)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1942-1943, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Anti-Vivisection, 1949-1950 (Box 8)
  - Atomic Bomb, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Bibliography, [1920s-1950s] (Box 8)
  - Biographical Material, [1920s-1950s] (Box 8)
    -see also Ser. I, American Men of Science
  - Biological Dinner Club, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - Bowman, Isaiah, 1948 (Box 8)
  - "Bug Battery", 1962-1963 (Box 8)
    See folder for complete list of correspondents
    Life
  - Burnet (Box 8)
    -see Ser. II, JHU Medical School, Lectures
  - "Chart for Gourmets" (Box 8)
    -see Oversized
  - Chinard, Francis P., [1951] (Box 8)
  - Cinquantenaire De La Mort De Pasteur Comité Du Cinquantenaire De La Mort De Pasteur, 1946; 2 folders (Box 8)
    French Embassy
    Heidelberger, Michael
    Institut Pasteur
    Rapkine, Louis
    Union Nationale Des Intellectuels
  - Clark, Anna Mansfield, [1956] (Box 8)
  - Clippings from Scientific Periodicals, 1958-1962, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Clippings Re: Clark and others, JHU, etc., 1920s-1960s (Box 8)
  - Cohen, Barnett, 1952-1953, n.d. (Box 8)
  - "Barnett Cohen, 1891-1952: An Appreciation", 1952-1953 (Box 8)
    Baldwin, I. L
    Berry, George Packer
    Brown, Claude P.
    Caraway, Wendell
    Carnes William H.
    Chambers, Robert
    Clark, Paul F.
    Cohen, Aaron
    Otto, Gilbert
    Niles, Emory H.
    Porter, Curt C.
    Reznikoff, Paul
    (Mrs. William)
    Van Renn[selaer],
    Weinbach, Eugene C.
    Weissman, Norman
  - Cohn, Edwin J. (Box 8)
  - Conference on Biological Antioxidants (3rd), October 7-8, 1948 (Box 8)
    -see also Ser. V, Michaelis, Leonor. "The Mechanism of Autoxidation..."
  - Conference on Energy Relationships in Enzyme Reactions, 1944 (Box 8)
    -see also Ser. I, The New York Academy of Sciences
  - Conference on Trace Elements, 1948 (Box 8)
    12-13 April 1948
  - Cowgill, Robert W., 1946 (Box 8)
  - Cutter Lecture on Preventive Medicine (Box 8)
    -see Ser. II, Harvard University. Cutter Lecture on Preventive Medicine
  - Charles E. Dohme Memorial Lectureship (Box 8)
  - Ensor, Lowell Skinner (Box 8)
    -see Ser. II, Western Maryland College
  - "Evolution Toward a Mature Scientific Literature", 1934, 1939, 1951, n.d. (Box 8)
    B[enton], Anne
    Buchanan, R. E.
    Earle, C. A.
    Emmett,
    Hill, Jus[?]
    Lynch, Ruth S.
    Peltier, George L.
    Reynolds, H.
    S[?], Jim M.
    Van Niel, C. B.
    Vaughn, Reese H.
  - Gamma Alpha (Graduate Scientific Fraternity), 1938, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Gas Rationing Board, 1942, 1944 (Box 8)
  - Genealogy, 1929, 1950, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Golfing, 1932-1944 (Box 8)
  - Goodpasture, Ernest W. (Box 8)
  - Goucher College, 1949 (Box 8)
  - Groves, Leslie R., 1945 (Box 8)
  - Harbury, Henry, [1963] (Box 8)
  - Harvard University. Cutter Lecture on Preventive Medicine, 1930 (Box 8)
    -see also Ser. IV, "The Cutter Lectures..."
  - Hastings, A. Baird, [ca. 1931] (Box 8)
  - Herter Lectures (Box 8)
  - International Physiological Congress (XIII), 1929 (Box 8)
  - Invitations (Box 8)
    - Folder 1, 1929-1947 (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1948-1953, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Jette, Eric R. (Box 8)
    -see Ser. II, Pennsylvania State College. Priestley Lectures
  - Frank B. Jewett Fellowships in the Physical Sciences, 1944 (Box 8)
  - Johns Hopkins Medical History Club (Box 8)
    -see Ser. II, Sigerist, Henry E.
  - JHU, 1930s-1950s (Box 9)
  - JHU Biochemistry and Physical Chemistry Courses, 1935, 1952-1955 (Box 9)
  - JHU Commemoration Day Exercises, 1933-1938, 1946-1948, 1954 (Box 9)
  - JHU Commencement Exercises, 1948-1950 (Box 9)
  - JHU Medical School, 1946, 1951, 1953 (Box 9)
  - JHU Medical School, Commencement Exercises, 1945 (Box 9)
  - JHU Medical School, Lectures, 1929-1937, 1952 (Box 9)
  - JHU Medical School, Pithotomy Club (Box 9)
  - JHU Remsen Memorial Lectures, 1952-1953 (Box 9)
  - "Biographical Memoir of Walter (Jennings) Jones, 1865-1935", 1939 (Box 9)
    Clarke, William L.
    Enders, Howard E.
    Guttmacher, Dorothy E.
    Jones, Benjamin B.
    [Wright],
  - Kelly, Howard A., n.d. (Box 9)
  - Kraushaar, Otto Frederick, 1949 (Box 9)
    -see Ser. II, Goucher College
  - Laboratory Equipment, 1952-1953, n.d. (Box 9)
    inventories & lists
  - Lehninger, A. L., [1951] (Box 9)
  - Liebig Wöhler Feier (Darmstadt), 1928 (Box 9)
  - Lubs, H. A., 1956 (Box 9)
  - Magazine Subscriptions, 1960-1963, n.d. (Box 9)
    incl. corresp.
  - Meyer, Adolf, 1937 (Box 9)
  - Milk Testing Apparatus Brochure, 1928 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1953, 1957 (Box 9)
  - Name Lists, 1953, 1956, n.d. (Box 9)
  - NAS, 1932-1955 (Box 9)
  - NAS Advisory Committee on Biologic Warfare, [1946], n.d. (Box 9)
  - National Defense Research Committee, 1942 (Box 9)
    WMC's personnel security questionnaire
  - NRC, 1942-1946 (Box 9)
  - NRC Antimalarial Drug Program, [ca. 1943-1947] (Box 9)
  - "Notes on a Half-Century of Research, Teaching and Administration", 1962 (Box 9)
    Alphabetical by surname; see folder for complete list of correspondents
    Gladding, Harriet (Clark)
    Lehninger, A. L.
    McCollum, E. V.
    Sumner, Margaret (Clark)
    -see also Ser. IV, "Notes on a Half-Century..."
  - Oxidation-Reduction Potentials of Organic Systems, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
    Bates, Roger G.
    Cowgill, Robert
    Fruton, Joseph
    Krebs, H. A.
    Preisler, Paul
  - Park, Edwards A., 1938 (Box 9)
  - Passano Award, 1945-1946 (Box 9)
  - Patent. Humidostat-Regulator, 1912 (Box 9)
  - Pennsylvania State College. Priestley Lectures, 1933 (Box 9)
  - Playbills and Entertainment Event Programs, 1936-1950s (Box 9)
  - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1943-1945 (Box 9)
    WMC lecture, 19 Oct. 1944
  - The Presbyterian Hospital of the City of Chicago, 1947 (Box 9)
    WMC lecture, 7 March 1947
  - Remsen Memorial Lectures (Box 9)
    -see Ser. II, JHU Remsen Memorial Lectures
  - St. Andrew's Society of Baltimore, 1948, 1953-1954 (Box 9)
  - Schmelkes, Franz Carl, 1942 (Box 9)
  - Sigerist, Henry E., 1947 (Box 9)
  - Sigma Xi, 1937 (Box 9)
  - The Society of American Bacteriologists (Box 9)
    - Folder 1, 1927-1941 (Box 9)
    - Folder 2, 1950, 1955 (Box 9)
  - Stiles, Charles Wardell, 1931 (Box 9)
  - Symposium on Biophysics (American Institute of Physics), 1937 (Box 9)
    4-6 Nov. 1937
  - Symposium on Carbohydrate Metabolism (Box 9)
    -see Ser. II, JHU Medical School
  - Symposium on Hemin Pigments and Chromoproteins (NAS?), 1948 (Box 9)
    18 March 1948
  - Symposium on Metalloporphyrins and Heme Proteins (NAS?) (Box 9)
    Wednesday Morning
  - Symposium on the Biochemistry of Malarial Parasites and the Mode of Action of Antimalarial Drugs (Box 9)
  - William Sidney Thayer and Susan Read Thayer Lectureship in Clinical Medicine (Box 9)
    -see Ser. II, JHU Medical School, Lecture Programs
  - Trinity Military Institute, 1938 (Box 9)
  - US Copyright Office. Certificate of Copyright Registration, [1946] (Box 9)
  - US Public Health Service, 1927 (Box 9)
  - University of Chicago, 1927 (Box 9)
  - University of Maryland, 1927 (Box 9)
  - Vassar College, 1928 (Box 9)
    Lecture calendar including note regarding lecture by Clark.
  - Weed, Lewis Hill, [1948] (Box 9)
    Portrait.
  - Welch, William Henry, 1950 (Box 9)
  - Western Maryland College, 1947 (Box 9)
  - Willard, Daniel, 1941 (Box 9)
  - Williams College, 1903, [ca. 1946] (Box 9)
    Tuition receipt; alumni news
  - Wrinch, Dorothy, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Yale University. Russell H. Chittenden Lecture in Biochemistry, "Remarks on a Limited Chemical Continuum," by William Mansfield Clark (Box 9)
- Series III. Research notes, 1907-1962; 3 boxes, 1.25 lin. feet
  Research notes, notebooks, and calculations made by Clark in the course of laboratory work, and the writing of manuscripts intended for publication. Also included are six folders of material containing "data on dyes." These folders include notes and calculations made by Clark and Barnett Cohen, and seem to date from 1927-1951. Correspondence found with this material, largely between Cohen and others, has been photocopied. The photocopies remain in Series III, while the originals were moved to Series I. Other material (ca. 1960's) concerns work on indophenols, and papers published by Clark's one-time student, and later professor of biochemistry at Yale University, Henry Harbury. Harbury's articles, co-authored with Paul A. Loach, detail aspects of heme peptides, and ligand systems. Also included is material regarding work by John Gryder. In addition, this series contains seven notebooks which relate to Clark's class work, and to his lab on Hopkins' Homewood campus. The class notebooks include notes on optics, physical chemistry, and physics and thermodynamics. Notebooks regarding the Homewood lab (ca. 1953) include the following: "Calibrations & Standards", "Miscellaneous Experiments, Oct. 1953", and "Preparations." Other items in this series include a book of personal accounts (1907-1911), and 16 engagement books (Nov. 1941-June 1947) which cover the period of Clark's involvement with U.S. Government programs during World War II.
  - Cohen, Barnett. "Data on Dyes" (Box 10)
    - Folder 1, [1927?] (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, [1927?] (Box 10)
    - Folder 3, [1951?] (Box 10)
    - Folder 4, n.d. (Box 10)
    - Folder 5, 1928 (Box 10)
    - Folder 6, 1927-31 (Box 10)
  - "... [John] Gryder's System"--Calculations, n.d. (Box 10)
  - "[John] Gryder's Theory"--Calculations and Notes (Box 10)
  - Harbury, Henry and Paul A. Loach, [ca. 1960] (Box 10)
    "Heme Peptides"
  - Harbury, Henry and Paul A. Loach--Notes, [ca. 1960] (Box 10)
  - "Indophenols"--Notes, [ca. 1921-22] (Box 10)
  - "Ligand Systems"--Calculations, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Calculations (Box 10)
    - Folder 1, n.d. (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, [1960] (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Experiments, [ca. 1921-1930] (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Notes From the Literature, n.d.; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - "Miscellaneous Oxidation-Reduction", [1934?] (Box 11)
  - Notebooks #1, [ca. 1908-1910], 1920 (Box 11)
    "Optics"
    "Physical Chemistry"
    "Physics; Thermodynamics"
    "II"
  - Notebooks #2, [ca. 1953- ] (Box 11)
    "Calibrations & Standards"